Breaking out this November.
Leo is a animation, comedy, family film directed by David Wachtenheim.
Jaded 74-year-old lizard Leo has been stuck in the same Florida
classroom for decades with his terrarium-mate turtle.
When he learns he only has one year left to live, he plans to escape to experience life on the outside but instead gets
caught up in the problems of his anxious students — including an impossibly mean substitute teacher.
Leo (voice), played by Adam Sandler.
Squirtle (voice), played by Bill Burr.
Mrs. Malkin  (voice), played by Cecily Strong.
Jayda's Dad (voice), played by Jason Alexander.
Principal (voice), played by Rob Schneider.
Mrs. Salinas (voice), played by Allison Strong.
Leo (also marketed as Leo: Bloody Sweet) is a 2023 Indian
Tamil-language action thriller film directed by Lokesh Kanagaraj.
Produced by Seven Screen Studio, it is the third
instalment in the Lokesh Cinematic Universe.
Partially inspired by the  David Cronenberg film A History of Violence, Leo stars Vijay in the titular role, alongside Sanjay Dutt, Arjun,
Trisha, Gautham Vasudev Menon, Mysskin, Madonna Sebastian, George Maryan, Mansoor Ali Khan, Priya Anand and Mathew Thomas.
In the film, Parthi, an outwardly humble man, draws the attention of gangsters Antony and
Harold Das who insist he is Antony's son Leo, previously presumed dead.
The film was officially announced in January 2023 under the tentative title Thalapathy 67, as it is
Vijay's 67th film as a lead actor, and the official title was announced a few days later.
Principal photography commenced the same month in Chennai along with a sporadic schedule in Kashmir, which
was again followed by another schedule held at the former location, and wrapped by mid-July.
The film has music composed by Anirudh Ravichander, cinematography
handled by Manoj Paramahamsa and editing by Philomin Raj.
Leo was released worldwide on 19 October 2023 in standard and IMAX formats to mixed reviews from critics, with praise
for Vijay's performance, technical aspects and action sequences while the writing received criticism.
It set several box office records for a Tamil film, emerging as the second highest-grossing Tamil film of 2023, the seventh highest-grossing Indian film of
2023, third highest-grossing Tamil film of all time, the highest-grossing Tamil film overseas and the highest-grossing film in Tamil Nadu.
The film explores themes of midlife crisis, classroom,
musical, school, unlikely friendship.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.